# Francisco Andres Sarría

### **Front-end Developer**

linkedin.com/in/francisco-andres-sarria franasarria@gmail.com +54 351 6193912

### **Profile**

Proficient Front-End Developer with 1,5+ years of experience designing and developing web apps and web sites. Specializes in React.js and Next.js with responsive design approach (mobile first).

In all the projects in which I worked I've not only accomplished my task but also proposed solutions, additions or different ways to deliver value.

Motivated to keep growing with new challenges and projects.

## Technology & methodology

JavaScript, React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, HTML, CSS/SASS, Material UI, PrimeReact, TailwindCSS, Vite, Git/GitHub, Azure DevOps, AWS, Adobe XD, Figma, JIRA, Agile Methodologies, Scrum.

## Languages

English: B2/C1 (Upper Intermediate/Advanced). Took T.O.E.F.L. exam in 2004.

Worked in a call center from 2004 to 2005 as customer service for MCI (American phone company) and from 2005 to 2006 I worked as ticket seller for Ski Co in Aspen, USA.

### Work experience - 1/2

#### **Incluit powered by Avenga**

March 2022 - November 2023

#### **Argentinian Health Company - September to November 2023**

Authentication and authorization gateway for every app they have.

This has been developed with AWS Cognito and custom AWS Lambdas.

I was in charge of the front-end.

In the first Epic I developed the custom login page due AWS Cognito login page lacks the possibility to be translated and features very basic customizations options. Additionally, the login needed accessibility compliance. The main technology stack was React.js, TypeScript, axios and Tailwind.

The second epic in the project for the front-end was to develop an admin panel for the RBAC (Roll-Based Access Control). The main technology stack was React.js, axios, PrimeReact, TypeScript. Azure DevOps as project management tool, repository and documentation.

Referral: Raúl Zambrano, P.M. - https://www.linkedin.com/in/raulzambrano/

#### **Brazilian Insurance Company - December 2022 to May 2023**

Development of an insurance management platform.

I contributed to develop the front end in React.js, Typescript, Redux and a customized MUI components library.

Help develop a multi-step form and submission system.

Design a new end user app for easy and fast MercoSur car insurance acquisition

Environment and Tools: Node.js, React.js, Customized MUI components, React-Redux. Jira for the project management tool and Gitlab as repository and version control.

Referral: Darío Bosio - https://www.linkedin.com/in/dario-bosio-4a167356/

#### **Argentinian Telecommunication Company - September to December 2022**

Development of an I.D.P. (Internal Developer Platform).

Responsibilities: Worked in a big team of back-ends and full-stack developers and I contributed to develop the front end in React.js, help migrating from MUI 4 to MUI 5, I added the Dark Mode with MUI 5, and took on the task of designing new services screens with Figma.

Environment and Tools: Node.js, React.js, MUI, Vite.js. As project manager tool we used Jira and Gitea as version control system and repository.

Referral: Javier Zoppetti - https://www.linkedin.com/in/javier-zoppetti-9b3800b/

#### **American Telecommunication Company- March to August 2022**

Development of an ie-commerce web site with Drupal and Vue.js.

Responsibilities: Help to understand and manage the Drupal CMS.

Contribute with the Vue.js and CSS part of the web application.

Environment and Tools: Drupal 9, Vue.js 3, Acquia Cloud Platform, Bitbucket as version control system and repository.

# Work experience - 2/2

#### Persuasiva

January 2020 – April 2022

#### Web Designer / Web Developer

Argentinian communication agency based in Córdoba city.

Responsibilities: Design websites, develop web sites with Wordpress, developing newsletters and managing the distribution.

Environment and Tools: Wordpress, regular shared hosting solutions, Mailchimp

and similar, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator.

Referral: Daniel Gomez - https://www.linkedin.com/in/supremodesconocido/

### Education

#### Platzi - Programming, Development and Front-end

November 2019 – Present

https://platzi.com/p/francisco-sarria/

#### YouTube, FreeCodeCamp, Udemy, DevTo, Official Documentation...

November 2019 – Present

Referents: Kent C. Dodds, Web Dev Simplified, MiduDev, Dave Gray, Vercel, Lee Robinson, Mat Pocock, Traversy Media, Fernando Herrera, LogRocket, Kevin Powell, and many more.

#### IES Siglo 21 - Multimedia Design

2008 – 2012

#### Lino E. Spilimbergo - Photography

2007 - 2009

# **Contact info**

https://fransarria2022.vercel.app/ linkedin.com/in/francisco-andres-sarria franasarria@gmail.com +54 351 6193912